<resources>
    <string name="app_name">calmscient</string>
    <string name="splash_science">The Science of Calm</string>
    <string name="welcome_message">Welcome to my app!</string>
    <string name="username">Username</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="forgot_password">Forgot password?</string>
    <string name="create_new_account">Create an new account</string>
    <string name="or">or</string>
    <string name="happy_to_see_you">We are happy to see you</string>
    <string name="hello">Hello</string>
    <string name="home">HOME</string>
    <string name="discovery">DISCOVERY</string>
    <string name="discovery_lower">Discovery</string>
    <string name="exercises">EXERCISES</string>
    <string name="exercises_lower">Exercises</string>
    <string name="rewards">REWARDS</string>
    <string name="rewards_lower">Rewards</string>
    <string name="my_medical_records">My Medical Records</string>
    <string name="weekly_summary">Weekly Summary</string>
    <string name="favorites">Favorites</string>
    <string name="need_to_talk">Need to talk with someone?</string>
    <string name="good_morning"><b>Good Morning!</b></string>
    <string name="good_afternoon"><b>Good Afternoon!</b></string>
    <string name="good_evening"><b>Good Evening!</b></string>
    <string name="mood_right_now"><b>How is your mood right now?</b></string>
    <string name="day_today"><b>How was your day?</b></string>
    <string name="bad"><b>BAD</b></string>
    <string name="be_better"><b>COULD BE BETTER</b></string>
    <string name="fair"><b>FAIR</b></string>
    <string name="good"><b>GOOD</b></string>
    <string name="excellent"><b>EXCELLENT</b></string>
    <string name="spend_time"><b>Who did you spend time with?</b></string>
    <string name="family"><b>FAMILY</b></string>
    <string name="friends"><b>FRIENDS</b></string>
    <string name="workmates"><b>WORKMATES</b></string>
    <string name="others"><b>OTHERS</b></string>
    <string name="alone"><b>ALONE</b></string>
    <string name="take_medic_evening"><b>Did you take your meds this evening?</b></string>
    <string name="take_medic_morning"><b>Did you take your meds this morning?</b></string>
    <string name="hours_night"><b>How many hours did you sleep last night?</b></string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="daily_journal"><b>Daily Journal</b></string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="medications">Medications</string>
    <string name="medication_Details">Medications Details</string>
    <string name="upcoming_medical_appointments">Upcoming Medical Appointments</string>
    <string name="screenings">Screenings</string>
    <string name="add_appointment">Add AppointmentAgregar cita</string>
    <!--network errors-->
    <string name="network_connection_error">Internet connection lost, please retry again</string>
    <string name="network_default_error">Something wrong happened, please retry again</string>
    <string name="network_internal_error">Our systems got an error, please retry again</string>
    <string name="network_server_not_available">Our services are under maintenance, please retry after some time
    </string>
    <string name="network_invalidation_error">Username or password is incorrect,Please retry again</string>
    <string name="server_connection_error">Not able to connect, please retry again</string>
    <string name="network_login_again">Please log in again</string>
    <string name="strAlertMessage_Something">Something is not right here try again later</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home_fragment">Something is not right here try again later</string>

    <string name="no_appointments">No Appointments</string>
    <string name="hospital_name1" translatable="false">SCD Hospital</string>
    <string name="doctor_name1"><b>Dr. Hannah Johnso</b></string>

    <string name="provider">Provider</string>
    <string name="dosage">Dosage</string>
    <string name="direction">Direction</string>
    <!--settings-->
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="profile">Profile</string>
    <string name="theme">Theme</string>
    <string name="dark_mode">Dark Mode</string>
    <string name="language">Language</string>
    <string name="english">English</string>
    <string name="spanish">Spanish</string>
    <string name="asl">ASL</string>
    <string name="notifications">Notifications</string>
    <string name="license_key">License Key</string>
    <string name="help_support">Help &amp; Support</string>
    <string name="logout">Logout</string>

    <string name="add_medications">Add Medications</string>
    <string name="alarm">Alarm</string>
    <string name="repeat">Repeat</string>
    <string name="everyday">Every Day</string>
    <string name="time">Time</string>
    <string name="schedule_time_and_alarm">Schedule Time &amp; Alarm</string>
    <string name="with_meal">With Meal</string>
    <string name="morning">Morning</string>
    <string name="evening">Evening</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <!--discovery-->
    <string name="anxiety">Managing anxiety</string>
    <string name="stress">Changing your response to stress</string>
    <string name="control">Taking control</string>
    <string name="terms">Accept <u>Terms and Conditions</u></string>
    <!--Emergency Resource Page strings-->
    <string name="emergency_resource">Emergency Resource</string>
    <string name="doctor_name">Dr. Samuel Parker</string>
    <string name="hospital_name">Central Park Hospital</string>
    <string name="doctor_phone_number"><u><a href="tel:(804)0938172"><font color="#6E6BB3">(804)0938172</font></a></u></string>
    <string name="suicide_heading">988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline</string>
    <string name="suicide_text">Call or text 988 or chat 988lifeline.org. The 988 Suicide &amp; Crisis Lifeline is a national network of local crisis centers that provides free and confidential emotional support to people in suicidal crisis or emotional distress 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</string>
    <string name="disaster_heading">Disaster Distress Helpline</string>
    <string name="disaster_text">The national Disaster Distress Helpline is available for anyone experiencing emotional distress related to natural or human-caused disasters.Call or text <u><a href="tel:1-800-985-5990"><font color="#6E6BB3">1-800-985-5990</font></a></u> to be connected to a trained, caring counselor, 24/7/365.
</string>
    <string name="crisis_heading">Crisis Text Line</string>
    <string name="crisis_text">Text MHA to<a href="sms:678678"><font color="#6E6BB3"> 741741</font></a> and you\'ll be connected to a trained Crisis Counselor. Crisis Text Line provides free, text-based support 24/7.</string>
    <string name="trevor_heading">The Trevor Project</string>
    <string name="trevor_text">
        Call <u><a href="tel:1-866-488-7386"><font color="#6E6BB3">1-866-488-7386</font></a></u> or text START to <a href="sms:678678"><font color="#6E6BB3">678678</font></a>.A national 24-hour, toll free confidential suicide hotline for LGBTQ youth.
</string>
    <string name="trans_helpline_heading">Trans Lifeline</string>
    <string name="trans_helpline_text">Dial <u><a href="tel:877-565-8860"><font color="#6E6BB3">877-565-8860</font></a></u> for US and <u><a href="tel:877-330-6366"><font color="#6E6BB3">877-330-6366</font></a></u> for Canada.Trans Lifeline\'s Hotline is a peer support service run by trans people, for trans and questioning callers.
</string>
    <string name="disaster_number">1-800-985-5990</string>
    <string name="crisis_number">741741</string>
    <string name="trevor_number">1-866-488-7386</string>
    <string name="trans_number">877-565-8860</string>
    <string name="next_appointments">Next appointments</string>
    <string name="date_time">Date &amp; Time</string>
    <string name="contact">Date &amp; Time</string>
    <string name="address">Date &amp; Time</string>
    <string name="appointments_details">Appointment Details</string>
    <string name="your_history">History</string>
    <string name="your_results">Your Results</string>
    <string name="summary_takingcontrol">Summary</string>
    <string name="glossary">Glossary</string>
    <string name="torch_national"><u>US National Institute of Health American Psychological Association Stanford University</u></string>
    <string name="torch_phq">PHQ9 Copyright \u00a9 Pfizer Inc. All rights reserved.Reproduced with permission. PRIME-MD \u00AE is a trademark of Pfizer Inc.</string>
    <!--Anxiety-->
    <string name="manage_anxiety">Manage anxiety</string>
    <string name="managing_anxiety">Managing anxiety</string>
    <string name="introduction">Introduction</string>
    <!--lesson1.2-->
    <string name="title_toolbar_pace">Get yourself out of “fast pace cycle</string>
    <string name="title_pace">We are all stressed out…</string>
    <string name="desc_one_pace">Most of us work too much, schedule too much, and hear about too many negative events in the world. Sometimes, you can’t avoid any of it. </string>
    <string name="desc_two_pace">Here’s your first task on your journey toward peace of mind:</string>
    <string name="checkbox_pace">Choose a time and place to devote to this mental wellness discovery..</string>
    <string name="title_third_pace">What should you do during these 15 minutes?</string>
    <string name="desc_third_one_pace">During this course, you’ll be given lots of positive and productive things to think about. During each 15 minute session, set a timer on your phone so you can responsibly disconnect from the other things you might have scheduled. In your mind, shut the door on all the noisy thoughts you may be used to and enjoy the time you’ve dedicated toward improving your mental health. </string>
    <string name="title_third_two_pace">Make sure to set a reminder for the time and place you specified above.</string>

    <string name="set_reminder">Set reminder:</string>
    <string name="set_timer">Set timer:</string>
    <string name="other">Other?</string>
    <string name="write_a_place">Write a place</string>

    <!--Screenings-->
    <string name="phq">Over the last 2 weeks, how often have you been bothered by any of the following problems?</string>
    <string name="gad">Over the last 2 weeks, how often have you been bothered by any of the following problems?</string>
    <string name="audit">Do you enjoy a drink now and then\nMany of us do, often when socializing with friends and family. Lets take a look at your drinking patterns and how they may affect your health.\nThe AUDIT questionnaire is designed to help in the self-assessment of alcohol consumption and to identify any implications for the persons health and well being, now and in the future.</string>
    <string name="dast">Drug use refers to the use of prescribed or over‐the‐counter drugs in excess of the directions, and any non medical use of drugs.
        \nThe various classes of drugs may include cannabis , solvents , tranquilizers, barbiturates, cocaine, stimulants, hallucinogens or narcotics . The questions do not include alcoholic beverages.\nPlease answer every question. If you have difficulty with a statement, then choose the response that is mostly right.</string>

    <string name="afternoon">Afternoon</string>
    <string name="add_time_alarm">Add Time &amp; Alarm</string>
    <string name="page_1.1">DID YOU KNOW?</string>
    <string name="page_2.1">What is anxiety?</string>
    <string name="lets_begin_btn">Let\'s Begin!</string>
    <string name="lets_begin_are_ready">Are you ready?</string>
    <string name="lets_begin">The Calmscient discovery will only be as effective as you make it. \nSo be determined to dedicate time to following along and completing the exercises. Each section has interesting and informative content that is designed to keep you actively thinking about your specific challenges. But, like taking a road trip to an unknown destination, you’ll need to be committed to following the map! It may be a little more work than you’re used to, but it will absolutely pay off in the end.</string>
    <string name="page_7.1"><font color="#6E6BB3">If a person could simply “remember” past experiences,</font></string>
    <!-- lesson 1-->
    <string name="lesson1_video_summary" translatable="false">
        Anxiety is a normal brain response to stress. The Fight, Flight, and Freeze responses help us meet the demands of potential threats. Things that can cause anxiety are:<br />
        \n
        &#8226; Encountering past threats\n
        &#8226; Unknown risks, changes, or results\n
        &#8226; Lack of skill or support\n
        Our nervous system is not broken! Learning to control it is an important and powerful skill we can master in order to keep stressful situations in their place.
</string>

    <string name="lesson1_video1_description">
    Our brain is like a computer. It has a basic operating system that helps us deal with the normal, day-to-day tasks and complexities of life. But when it detects a threat that can interrupt or damage normal operation, an alarm activates that immediately alerts us to the danger.\n\n
    You can imagine why this “Threat Alert” in our nervous system always takes priority. It’s so that we can get back to normal operations as quickly as possible. When this threat system is triggered, stress responses such as Fight/Flight/Freeze are activated. Stress hormones, such as adrenaline and cortisol, flood our system in order to meet the demands of the danger. Intense emotions, such as anxiety, fear and feeling overwhelmed, can overtake our mind.\n\n
    Understandably, general brain functions slow down or may be put “on hold” until the danger is taken care of. This is why we might feel that our thinking capacity diminishes when we are experiencing anxiety. Our “Threat Alert” system is an important part of our brain function, but when it is constantly engaged, enjoying life or having a full sense of self becomes difficult and may even feel out of reach.\n\n
    What are some things that can activate our “Threat Alert” system? They can be:\n
    …the thought that we might encounter situations or people that threatened us in the past.\n
    …unknown risks, unknown changes or unknown results when making a decision.\n
    …facing a challenging situation that we don’t think we have enough skills or support to overcome.\n\n
    Remember: anxiety is a normal brain response to stress. Our nervous system is not broken and there is nothing wrong with us when we feel anxious! Learning to control it is an important and powerful skill we can master in order to keep stressful situations in their place.\n
</string>
    <string name="lesson4_video1_description">
                A calm mind can only start with a calm body. Why is that?\n\n
        Remember: anxiety is our body’s response to danger, whether real or imagined. So if we can control our body, we can suppress our mind from responding with overwhelming worry and rumination.\n\n
        The very beginning of anxiety starts with “body sensations”. As soon as we perceive them, we will learn to “press pause”, so to speak. Our goal is to lower our stress hormones and this will result in stabilizing our nervous system.\n
        Some of the best techniques include exercises for mindful breathing, progressive muscle relaxation, body movement and resource installation.\n\n
        These exercises will calm your stress response and give you the space to handle anxious thoughts and build healthy behaviors. This will result in physical and emotional betterment.\n\n
        Why don’t you practice some of these exercises for ten minutes every morning or right before bedtime? The key is consistency so that your body learns what it feels like to have a calm nervous system.\n\n
</string>

    <!--Exrercises-->

    <string name="mindfulness_exercises">Mindfulness – What is it?</string>
    <string name="butterflyhug_exercises">Touch and the Butterfly Hug</string>
    <string name="handover_esxercises">Hand Over Your Heart</string>
    <string name="mindfulwalking_exercises">Mindful Walking</string>
    <string name="dance_exercises">Movement: Dance</string>
    <string name="running_exercises">Movement: Running</string>
    <string name="body_moment_exercies">Mindful Body Movement</string>
    <string name="deepbreathing_exercises">Deep breathing</string>
    <string name="musclerelaxation_exercises">Progressive Muscle Relaxation</string>
    <!--    Exercise_items-->
    <string name="screen1">Have you ever caught your mind wandering or daydreaming while you are in the middle of a familiar or repetitive task? You could be walking, working or even driving your car, and your mind is miles away, perhaps fantasizing about going on vacation, thinking about your to-do list, or worrying about some upcoming event. In either case, you are not focusing on the current situation and not in touch with the ‘here and now’.  This mode of operation is often referred to as automatic pilot.</string>
    <string name="screen2">Mindfulness is the opposite of automatic pilot. It is about experiencing the world that is firmly in the ‘here and now’. This is referred to as the being mode. It liberates you from automatic and unhelpful thoughts and responses.</string>
    <string name="screen3_heading">How does mindfulness help with anxiety?</string>
    <string name="screen3_belowheading">When we allow our brain to enter automatic pilot mode too often, it can be at risk of being conditioned to be overly preoccupied about the future, past experiences or our emotions in negative ways. If we have fallen into this old and unhelpful habit, we can unlearn it and replace it with skills that help us resist ‘buying into’ automatic worry and anxiety. </string>
    <string name="screen4">Mindfulness reminds us that we don’t have to take immediate control of, remove or fix unpleasant experiences. Instead, we can identify and actively engage in something that will give us a sense of safety and connection.</string>
    <string name="screen5">As a simple example: Instead of focusing on how many miles you walked in the morning, can you be mindfully aware of the birds singing, actively feel the fresh air, and sense the changing of the season? When you connect your senses to nature, animals, people and your own body, you capture the attention of your nervous system, which in turn soothes your anxiety. When you return home, you will be in a better frame of mind and more prepared to face your day.</string>
    <string name="screen6">Which mindfulness exercises would you like to make part of your daily routine? Calmscient can remind you of some easy mindfulness routines that will help you stay in a healthy, being mode.</string>

    <!--butterfly_hug Screens Exercises-->

    <string name="butterflyScreen1_text1">Humans respond powerfully to touch. Gentle, affectionate touch helps calm the nervous system and can trigger the release of oxytocin, the attachment hormone. Interestingly, when it comes to releasing oxytocin, our bodies don’t differentiate between the touch of a loved one or our own touch as we hold ourselves.\n </string>
    <string name="butterflyScreen1_text2">When you are feeling upset, ungrounded, agitated or irritable, try giving yourself a hug or a gentle stroke on the cheek and see how it impacts the way you feel.</string>
    <string name="butterflyScreen2_text1">Interlock your thumbs to form a butterfly shape</string>
    <string name="butterflyScreen2_text2">Place both hands over your chest, and alternate tapping your middle finger just below your collarbone</string>
    <string name="butterflyScreen2_text3">Breathe slowly and deeply (abdominal breathing) while you mentally observe what is going through your mind and body—thoughts, images, sounds, odors, feelings, and physical sensation.</string>

    <!--    Hand over your heart Exercise-->
    <string name="handoveryourHeart_titletext">Hand Over Your Heart</string>
    <string name="handoveryourHeart_text"></string>

    <!--    Dancing Exercise-->
    <string name="dancingexercise_titletext">Movement: Dance</string>
    <string name="dancingexercises_text">Moving your body to music can be a fun and fast way to shift your state and reconnect with your body, rhythm and expression.</string>
    <!--bodymovemet Exercise-->
    <string name="bodymovementexercise_text">There are many movement routines that invite you to reconnect with your body. Pilates, yoga and other similar stretching exercises incorporate mindful awareness of movements and postures. Additionally, coordinating body movement and breath further potentiates your ability to shift your state.</string>
    <!--deepBreathingExercise-->
    <string name="deepbreathingexercise_text">Find a comfortable and quiet place to sit or lie down. You can also practice deep breathing while standing, but ensure you have proper balance and support. </string>
    <!--Anxiety cards introduction 1 -->
    <string name="anxiety_card1_text1">DID YOU KNOW?</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card1_text2">An estimated <font color="#6E6BB3">31.1% of U.S. adults</font> experience any anxiety disorder at some time in their lives.</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card1_text3">You’re not alone!</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card2_text1">What is anxiety?</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card2_text2">Simply put, Anxiety is a helpful survival mechanism</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card2_text3">Imagine an early human trying to survive out in the woods. As in most forms of life, several built-in survival mechanisms are passed along from one generation to the next through DNA, and are an important part of the survival of a species.</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card3_text1">Some of the responses to this survival mechanism are:</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card3_text2">FIGHT</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card3_text3">Face the threat head on!</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card4_text1">FIGHT</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card4_text2">Look for a way out!</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card5_text1">FREEZE</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card5_text2">Can’t move!</string>


    <string name="anxiety_card6_text1">But now imagine this person coming face-to-face with a hungry bear. Fight, Flight, or Freeze may not be enough to survive this encounter! A bear is much stronger, faster, and smarter for either of those responses.</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card6_text2">This is where the “Worry” survival mechanism comes into play.</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card7_text1">If a person could simply “remember” past experiences,  “Worry” could help them take measures to avoid or back away from dangers before they became life threatening.</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card7_text2">In this example, if the person spotted a hungry bear from a distance, they would remember the potential danger and take another route, or possibly remember and avoid the places where bears were actively hunting for food. In both cases, “Worry” would help them survive successfully.</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card7_text3">So, worrying is a helpful skill!</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card8_text1">But how does too much “Worry” affect us?</string>
    <string name="anxiety_card8_text2">We often called this excess of worry “Anxiety”.</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card9_text1">In our modern world, there are many bear-like situations we face every day. It’s easy to become conditioned to constantly trigger our “Worry” response in order to avoid the need to “Fight, Flight or Freeze”.\n\nBut overprotecting ourselves with anxiety often comes at the expense of our happiness. </string>
    <string name="anxiety_card9_text2">Excessive use of worry, rumination, or fear of being at the wrong place at the wrong time limits our ability to enjoy life.</string>

    <string name="anxiety_card10_text1">Remember: worry and anxiety are not your enemies! </string>
    <string name="anxiety_card10_text2">The key to more peace of mind lies in enhancing your understanding of both and then learning the skills to use them in the right moments and for the right amounts of time.</string>


    <!--Anxiety cards introduction 2 -->
    <string name="fast_pase_card1_text1">We are all stressed out…</string>
    <string name="fast_pase_card1_text2">Most of us work too much, schedule too much, and hear about too many negative events in the world. Sometimes, you can’t avoid any of it.</string>
    <string name="fast_pase_card1_text3">Here’s your first task on your journey toward peace of mind:</string>

    <string name="fast_pase_card2_text1">You’re looking for only <b>15 minutes</b> a day to methodically progress through the Calmscient courses…</string>
    <string name="fast_pase_card2_text2">When is a good time for you?</string>
    <string name="fast_pase_card2_text3">Great! You’ve taken some positive action, and that’s a bigger deal than you might think. </string>


    <string name="fast_pase_card3_text1">What should you do during these 15 minutes?</string>
    <string name="fast_pase_card3_text2">During this course, you’ll be given lots of positive and productive things to think about. <b>During each 15 minute session, set a timer on your phone</b> so you can responsibly disconnect from the other things you might have scheduled. In your mind, shut the door on all the noisy thoughts you may be used to and enjoy the time you’ve dedicated toward improving your mental health.</string>
    <string name="fast_pase_card3_text3">Make sure to set a reminder for the time and place you specified above. </string>

    <!--Anxiety cards Introduction 3 -->
    <string name="make_plan_card1_text1">Making a plan to tackle anxiety is like mapping a route to a destination.</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card1_text2">Seeing the whole journey at a glance can help you visualize your trip and be confident in how you will get there. Once the route is set, you know you’ll arrive if you follow all the indicated turns and directions. There will be fewer surprises and you will feel more in control.</string>

    <string name="make_plan_card2_text1">When faced with a situation that causes you anxiety, imagine that the “destination” is the other side of that stressful situation.</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card2_text2">Here is how navigating that stressful situation might look like:</string>

    <string name="make_plan_card3_text1">STEP 1</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card3_text2">BE AWARE OF WHAT’S AROUND YOU</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card3_text3">Take note of how your anxiety is impacting your emotions, choices and decisions. \n\nChange your thinking from: “Something must be wrong with me” to: “I just need to protect myself from my environment which is filled with anxiety-inducing things”.</string>

    <string name="make_plan_card4_text1">STEP 2</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card4_text2">SPOT YOUR ANXIETY TRIGGERS</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card4_text3">Take note of which specific situations, thoughts or feelings trigger your anxiety and even write them down somewhere. Where possible, this will help you take action to avoid anxiety-inducing situations and learn to manage the ones you have no control over.</string>


    <string name="make_plan_card5_text1">STEP 3</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card5_text2">REMEMBER THAT YOU ARE NOT AN ANXIOUS PERSON</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card5_text3">Learn to identify the three components of anxiety: Physiological (Body), Cognitive (Mind) and Behavioral (Actions). This will help to follow action plans that calm your mind, body and actions. </string>


    <string name="make_plan_card6_text1">STEP 4</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card6_text2">IMPLEMENT BODY CALMING SKILLS</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card6_text3">You can learn to force your body to calm down. Once your body is calm, your mind will follow. Skills such as relaxation, progressive muscle relaxation, mindful breathing and walking will become second nature.</string>


    <string name="make_plan_card7_text1">STEP 5</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card7_text2">SET A MENTAL BOUNDARY BETWEEN YOU AND YOUR WORRIES</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card7_text3">There are ways to “delay” your worry until a designated “worry time” so you can focus on your daily routine without fearing that important things will be dropped.</string>


    <string name="make_plan_card8_text1">STEP 6</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card8_text2">IMPLEMENT MIND CALMING SKILLS</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card8_text3">Biased thinking (Cognitive Distortion) greatly affects our tendency to worry irrationally and causes persistent anxiety. This happens when, based on past experiences, we either underestimate or overestimate the stressors of a particular situation without looking at them realistically. In either case, it doesn’t allow us to see the situation clearly. Catching ourselves in Cognitive Distortion will help modify our thinking in a way that calms our</string>


    <string name="make_plan_card9_text1">YOU’VE ARRIVED!</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card9_text2">Congratulations! You’ve gotten to the other side of your stressful situation.</string>
    <string name="make_plan_card9_text3">If you map this same route every time, you’ll be able to navigate any stressful situation that comes your way.
\n\n What do you think of this action plan? Don’t worry if you aren’t sure of how to “drive” this path yet. This is why we are learning the skills one step at a time.
 </string>
    <string name="quiz_title">QUIZ</string>
    <string name="quiz_text1">It can be hard to clearly identify specific fears that trigger our anxiety cycles. In time, you’ll be able to quickly recognize and avoid them. To learn this skill, let’s walk through a series of questions together that will teach you to recognize, identify and understand your anxiety.</string>
    <string name="quiz_text2">1. Recognize the stressful situation(s):</string>
    <string name="quiz_text3">Over the last 30 days, have you been affected by the following problems?</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option1">Work related stress</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option2">Personal health stress</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option3">Family related stress</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option4">Social relations stress</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option5">Acute/chronic stress</string>
    <string name="quiz_text2_1">2. Identify your response </string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option2_1">Push Away/Avoidance (“I avoid stressful situations and people at any cost.”)</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option2_2">Push Through (“I try to ignore and push through stress.”)</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option2_3">Denial (“I either stay positive and push through or shutdown.”)</string>
    <string name="quiz_ques_3">3. Understand the consequences of your response: </string>
    <string name="quiz_ques_3_1">What happens to your anxiety as a result?</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option3_1">I end up giving up, rejecting, avoiding, and possibly losing important parts of my life, such as relationships, work, grades, time, and health.</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option3_2">I ignore stress, get overly productive, multitask, keep myself way too busy, get restless and seek quick relief from stress by unhelpful coping habits. Sometimes I get sick or injured.</string>
    <string name="quiz_text_option3_3">I have a hard time acknowledging my own stress and anxiety. I also have a hard time following through with changes in order to manage stress, and end up in a vicious cycle of anxiety.</string>
    <string name="submit">Submit</string>

</resources>